Make it special.
The Ringer is a comedy film directed by Barry W. Blaustein.
Pressured by a greedy uncle and a pile of debt, lovable loser Steve Barker resorts
to an unthinkable, contemptible, just-crazy-enough-to-work scheme.
He pretends to be mentally challenged to rig the upcoming
Special Olympics and bring home the gold.
But when Steve's fellow competitors get wise to the con, they inspire him to
rise to the greatest challenge of all: becoming a better person.
Steve Barker, played by Johnny Knoxville.
Gary Barker, played by Brian Cox.
Lynn Sheridan, played by Katherine Heigl.
Stavi, played by Luis Ávalos.
Glen, played by Jed Rees.
Mark, played by Leonard Earl Howze.
The Ringer is a 2005 American slapstick sports comedy starring Johnny Knoxville,
Katherine Heigl, and Brian Cox with cameos by Terry Funk and Jesse Ventura.
Directed by Barry W.
Blaustein, it was produced by the Farrelly brothers.
The film was released on December 23, 2005, by Fox Searchlight Pictures.
The plot centers around a young man (Knoxville) who, as part of a scheme to pay off his debts,
poses as being developmentally disabled to compete in the Special Olympics.
The film received mixed reviews, but its positive depiction of people with
disabilities was received approvingly by multiple commentators.
The film was also endorsed by the real-life Special Olympics.
The film explores themes of operation, sports, lawnmower, finger, loser.
The tone is lighthearted.